One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Mr. Iceburg
‫أيسبرغ-سان‬
This is great!
‫هذا رائع‬
Hey! I'm counting on you!
‫اسمع، أعتمد عليك‬
Who would've imagined these creatures could be so convenient!
‫من الرّائع وجود مخلوقات مريحة كهذه في العالم‬
It's a pretty smooth ride. Comfy, too!
‫لا يهتزّ كثيرًا ومريح‬
To the right! Right!
‫إلى اليمين، اليمين‬
The ball is headed your way! Here we go!
‫الكرة إليك‬
Ah! Stop the ball!
‫أوقف الكرة‬
Pass the ball! Pass the ball!
‫مرّر، مرّر‬
So cool!
‫هذا ممتع‬
Looks like a residential area.
‫تبدو هذه المنطقة منطقة سكنيّة‬
This town was certainly built with canals in mind.
‫إن هذه البلدة قد بُنيت حول القنوات حقًّا‬
Ah, there's an incline. Will we make it if we go against the current?
‫ثمّة تلّ، سنذهب عكس التّيّار ألا بأس؟‬
Can we go up?
‫أيمكننا الصعود؟‬
Wait! Wrong way! Go right! Right!
‫انتظر، أخطأت الطّريق، إلى اليمين، اليمين‬
They can even go uphill against the water, huh?
‫إذًا لا يهمّ‬ ‫وإن كانت تتدفق المياه إلى الأسفل؟‬
Not bad, you guys!
‫لستم سيئين يا رفاق‬
There are canals even on the rooftops!
‫حتّى أنّ القنوات تمتدّ فوق الأسطح‬
But we're going the wrong way! We have to go to the shopping district first!
‫لكنّنا سلكنا الطّريق الخطأ،‬ ‫علينا الذّهاب إلى منطقة التّسوّق أوّلًا‬
Oh? What's the hurry?
‫لا داعي من الاستعجال‬
It's not every day you get to walk along the canals.
‫هذه فرصة نادرة، دعينا نستكشف القنوات‬
Oh, that's right! We're at the top of the hill!
‫صحيح، نحن في قمّة التّلّ‬
Which... would mean...
‫ما يعني...‬
We're flying!
‫يا إلهي، كنّا نحلّق‬
We're falling. We're falling.
‫نحن نسقط، نسقط، نسقط، نسقط‬
We're falling. We're falling. We're falling.
‫نسقط، نسقط، نسقط...‬
– We're falling!
‫إننا نسقط‬
Don't be so reckless!
‫لا تغترّ بنفسك‬
Miss! Our goods are cheap!
‫يا آنسة، بضاعتنا رخيصة‬
How about taking a look at our products?
‫ما رأيك بإلقاء نظرة على المنتجات؟‬
We have lots of rare, quality items!
‫لدينا الكثير من البضائع الممتازة والنّادرة‬
Now starting our fifty-percent-off sale!
‫٪سنبدأ الآن تخفيضات بنسبة 50‬
Wow! This place got lively!
‫مذهل، أصبحت الأجواء حماسيّة‬
Oh? We ended up in the shopping district!
‫ماذا؟ انتهى بنا المطاف في منطقة التّسوّق‬
So what you took was actually a shortcut?
‫هل يعقل أنّكما أخذتما طريقًا مختصرًا؟‬
Sorry! You guys are pretty smart after all!
‫أنا آسفة، أنتما ذكيّان في الواقع‬
I've never been to such an energetic shopping district!
‫لم أزر قطّ منطقة تسوّق نشطة كهذه‬
Hey, check it out!
‫انظرا إلى ذلك، إنّه بُول ضخم‬
Whoa! Hey, it's headed this way!
‫عجبًا، إنّه قادم إلى هنا‬
This guy is scary!
‫إنّه مخيف‬
He'd eat us whole!
‫وكأنّه على وشك التهامنا‬
I wonder if it's a king size.
‫بالنّظر إلى حجمه، أتساءل إن كان من صنف كينغ‬
Huh? What's up with them?
‫ماذا؟ ما ذلك بالضّبط؟‬
Masks...?
‫أقنعة...‬
Wow, they're so elegant!
‫إنّها جميلة وفاتنة‬
Think it's some kind of party?
‫أتساءل إن كان هنالك حفل‬
What? What's going on?
‫ماذا؟ ما الّذي يجري؟‬
Come and get 'em! Hot and fresh hydro takoyaki!
‫تفضّل، هذا تاكوياكي طازج‬ ‫مصنوع من أخطبوط الماء-الماء‬
So, that's two hydro croquettes?
‫اثنان من كروكيت الماء-الماء؟‬
Both look yummy! Yagara, go over that way.
‫كلاهما يبدوان لذيذان، ياغارا اذهب إلى هناك‬
Hey! What's the big idea?!
‫مهلًا، إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟‬
Hey, Luffy! Where are you going?!
‫يا لوفي، إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟‬
Ask the yagara!
‫اسأل ياغارا‬
Welcome! What'll it be?
‫مرحبًا، ما هو طلبك؟‬
Oh, so you were hungry.
‫كنت جائعًا إذًا‬
Although it's normally for people, hydro meat is a yagara's favorite food.
‫لحم الماء-الماء هو طعام ياغارا المفضّل‬ ‫مع أنّه طعام البشر‬
Hydro? Then gimme ten!
‫ماء-ماء؟ أعطيني عشر شرائح إذًا‬
They're so good the cooks from Gourmet Town buy them in secret.
‫إنّها لذيذة جدًّا لدرجة أنّ الطّهاة من‬ ‫بلدة الذّوّاقة يأتون إلى هنا سرًّا لشرائها‬
It satisfies both body and soul, doesn't it?
‫إنّه يأسر جسدك وروحك، أليس كذلك؟‬
They... are... so... soft!
‫إنّه... ناعم... جدًّا‬
Yummy!
‫لذيذ‬
What?! It's that good?! Hey, Luffy! Toss one over here!
‫ماذا؟ أهو لذيذ بذلك القدر؟‬
No! Go buy your own!
‫كلّا، اشترِ واحدة بنفسك‬
Hey, Nami! Pull the boat over to that shop!
‫يا نامي، أوقفي القارب قرب ذلك المحل‬
More masks? They seem to be all over town.
‫المزيد من الأقنعة... بعد النّظر عن كثب،‬ ‫يبدو أنّها سائدة في البلدة بأكملها‬
Hey, Nami!
‫نامي‬
Okay!
‫والآن... سنذهب أخيرًا إلى جزيرة السفانة‬
A water gate elevator?
‫مصعد بوّابة مائي؟‬
It's that tower-like thing.
‫أي ذلك الشّيء الشّبيه بالبرج‬
Make your way inside, please!
‫ادخلوا رجاءً‬
The elevator leads up to Shipyard Island,
‫سيصعد المصعد إلى جزيرة السفانة‬
where you'll find the shipyards and downtown Water Seven!
‫ومصنع السّفن ووسط مدينة ووتر سيفن‬
Please make your way inside the gate!
‫أسرعوا بدخول البوّابة رجاءً‬
One minute until it closes!
‫تبقّت دقيقة على إغلاق البوّابة‬
What's gonna happen inside?
‫ماذا سيحدث في الدّاخل؟‬
Whoa! They closed the gate behind us!
‫مذهل، أُغلقت بوّابة الماء‬
We're going up! We're going up! We're going up!
‫نحن نصعد، نحن نصعد، نحن نصعد‬
I see. That happens. Then this happens.
‫فهمت، يحدث ذلك ثمّ هذا‬
Then it's this and that, which makes it a water gate elevator.
‫ثمّ يفعلون هذا وذاك‬ ‫ولهذا يسمّى مصعد بوّابة مائي‬
Whoa! Water Seven is pretty neat!
‫مذهل، إن ووتر سيفن شيّقة‬
So they use water for all sorts of things!
‫إذًا يستخدمون الماء لكافّة الأمور‬
Hey!
‫أنت‬
Who're you callin' "moss head"?
‫من تنعت بالطحلبي؟‬
Hey, Zoro.
‫يا زورو‬
Where's Robin? She isn't on the ship.
‫أين هي روبين-تشان؟ ليست في السّفينة‬
That's right. She and Chopper headed out earlier.
‫صحيح، خرجت مع تشوبّر سابقًا‬
She said she was going shopping.
‫قالت أنّها ستذهب للتّسوّق‬
What the hell?! Then you're the only one on the ship?!
‫ماذا؟ إذًا هل بقيت أنت فقط في السّفينة؟‬
What a letdown!
‫يا لها من بيئة مملّة‬
You got that right.
‫أوافقك الرأي‬
All right, then. I'm going grocery shopping.
‫حسنًا إذًا، سأذهب لشراء الموادّ الغذائيّة أيضًا‬
Watch the ship while I'm gone.
‫لذا احرص على مراقبة السّفينة جيّدًا‬
Hell, he's already asleep.
‫تبًّا، غطّ في النّوم بالفعل‬
Whatever. She's all yours.
‫حسنًا، سأترك السّفينة لك‬
We're here!
‫وصلنا‬
So this is downtown Water Seven and the world's greatest shipyard?!
‫هذا هو حوض السفانة الأوّل‬ ‫في العالم إذًا، وسط مدينة ووتر سيفن‬
It looks like there's more land than water around here.
‫كما توقّعت، أرى المزيد من اليابسة هنا‬
Everything's so huge!
‫كلّ شيء ضخم‬
I've never seen such a big city!
‫لم أرَ بلدة ضخمة كهذه قطّ‬
What's with that crowd?
‫ما قصّة ذلك الحشد؟‬
Are they gawking at the shipyard?
‫هل يشاهدون حوض السفانة؟‬
Let's check it out! Go, yagara!
‫لنذهب لرؤيته، هيّا بنا يا ياغارا‬
Hey, look over there! It's Lucci! He's so handsome!
‫انظروا هناك، إنّه لوتشي-سان‬ ‫إنّه وسيم جدًّا‬
Isn't Paulie here?
‫أليس باولي هنا؟‬
Lulu's here! So suave! He's truly a man among men.
‫لولو هنا، كم هو راقٍ ونعم الرّجل‬
But nobody's manlier than Tilestone!
‫من أكثر رجولة من تايلستون؟‬
Hey, pops.
‫أخبرني يا عمّ‬
Did something happen?
‫هل حدث شيء؟‬
Yeah, some pirates tried stirring up trouble at Dock One again.
‫نعم، يبدو أنّ بعض القراصنة‬ ‫افتعلوا جلبة هنا في الحوض الأول‬
But, it ended with the craftsmen knocking them out, as usual.
‫لكن انتهى الأمر عندما أطاح بهم الحرفيّون‬
There's no end to these idiots.
‫لا نهاية لأولئك الحمقى‬
The shipwrights can beat up pirates?
‫هزم سفانون قراصنة؟‬
Oh, you must be a seafarer.
‫لا بدّ أنّك رحّال‬
That crowd... Well, they're just busybodies.
‫ذلك الحشد... باختصار، فضوليّون‬
Everyone 'round here admires the Galley-La Company shipwrights.
‫يحظى سفانو شركة‬ ‫غاليلا بإعجاب كلّ السّكان‬
They're strong...
‫إنّهم أقوياء...‬
They're the pride of Water Seven.
‫إنّهم فخر ووتر سيفن‬
Wow! I can't wait to meet them!
‫مذهل، أتوق لمقابلتهم‬
Hey, Luffy!
‫يا لوفي‬
Let's hurry up and get to the currency exchange.
‫لنعجّل بالذّهاب إلى محلّ الصّرف‬
We can come back here later.
‫بإمكاننا أن نعود إلى هنا لاحقًا‬
Okay!
‫حسنًا‬
Backstreets Shopping District Water Seven
‫منطقة الأسواق في‬ ‫ووتر سيفن‬
This is the Backstreets shopping district.
‫مذكور أنّنا في منطقة تسوّق الشّارع الخلفيّ‬
They call a place this lively the Backstreets?
‫أيدعون مكانًا نشيطًا كهذا بالشّارع الخلفيّ؟‬
There're also places where we can walk, huh?
‫لديهم أماكن حيث نستطيع السّير إذًا؟‬
Clear water that matches a pristine city...
‫الماء صافٍ والبلدة جميلة‬
Yeah.
‫نعم‬
Whoa! What's that?!
‫عجبًا، ما ذلك؟‬
That's a mask shop.
‫إنّه محلّ أقنعة‬
I've noticed people are walking around town wearing those masks.
‫لاحظت أنّ النّاس يتجوّلون‬ ‫في البلدة مرتدين أقنعة‬
Oh, they're wearing masks? I just thought they had weird faces.
‫إنّهم يرتدونها إذًا؟‬ ‫ظننت أنّها وجوه غريبة‬
It seems San Faldo is holding a costume festival.
‫يبدو أنّهم يقيمون كرنفال أزياء كلّ يوم الآن‬
It's an island you can reach using the sea train.
‫في سان فالدو، جزيرة يمكنك‬ ‫الذّهاب إليها بأخذ القطار البحريّ‬
What? How do you know that?
‫ماذا؟ كيف تعرفين ذلك؟‬
People walking by are talking about it.
‫يتحدّث السّائرون عنها‬
I'm surprised that you can hear them.
‫أنا مندهش لأنّك تستطيعين سماعهم‬
It's a habit.
‫إنّها عادة...‬
Since childhood, I survived by listening to those around me and gauging their feelings.
‫عشتُ محاولةً الحكم والاستماع‬ ‫لمشاعر النّاس منذ نعومة أظافري‬
You're amazing, Robin.
‫أنت مذهلة يا روبين‬
Doctor...
‫سيّدي الطّبيب‬
Over there! It's a bookstore.
‫هناك، ثمّة مكتبة‬
Really?!
‫حقًّا؟‬
Can we?!
‫أيمكننا التّوقّف عندها؟‬
Of course! Let's go inside.
‫بالطبع، لندخل‬
Yay!
‫مرحى‬
I'm with CP9.
‫سي بي 9...‬
Robin! I'm gonna go in, okay?
‫روبين، سأبادر وأدخل، اتّفقنا؟‬
It should be fine if I'm in my human form.
‫ربّما لا بأس أن أتجول بهيئتي البشرية‬
Wow, what a neat mask! What're you dressed up as?
‫يا له من قناع رائع، ما الّذي تنتحله؟‬
Oh, y'know... A human reindeer.
‫نـ-نعم... إنسان رنّة‬
Glad you're having fun.
‫إن كنتَ مستمتعًا، فذلك ما يهمّ‬
Robin?
‫روبين؟‬
Hey!
‫مرحبًا؟‬
We thought we'd get you while you slept.
‫ظننتُ أنّنا سنهاجمك وأنت نائم...‬
Who are you creeps?!
‫من أنتم أيّها الأوغاد؟‬
Identify yourselves!
‫عرّفوا عن أنفسكم‬
O-One hundred million belly?!
‫مـ-مئة مليون بيري!‬
Currency Exchange
‫مصرف النقود‬
I-Idiot! You're too loud! Everyone can hear you!
‫أ-أيّها الغبيّ، لا تصرخ‬ ‫يمكن للجميع سماعك‬
Y-Y-You're gonna give us that much money?!
‫هـ-هل ستعطينا كلّ ذلك القدر من المال؟‬
L-Like... Like I said, Luffy, you're too loud!
‫كـ-كما أخبرتك يا لوفي، إنّك تصرخ‬
This is indeed worth that much.
‫إنّه يستحقّ ذلك القدر بالفعل‬
This is incredibly pure gold with historical significance.
‫إنّه ذهب عجيب، مع الأخذ بالاعتبار‬ ‫قيمته التّاريخيّة ونصاعته‬
With that much money, we can really fix the Merry!
‫مع ذلك القدر من المال، بإمكاننا‬ ‫إصلاح الميري على أتمّ وجه‬
Yeah! With money to spare!
‫أجل، حتّى أنّه سيبقى معنا مال إضافيّ‬
Nice! Then we use the rest to buy a bronze statue!
‫إذًا سننفق ما تبقّى من المال لشراء تمثال برونزيّ‬
No. No, we won't.
‫لا، لا تشتره‬
If you accept that amount, please sign and put your thumbprint here.
‫إن كنت راضيًا بهذا القدر،‬ ‫أرجو أن توقّع وتبصم هنا‬
I'll go prepare the cash immediately.
‫سأذهب لتجهيز المال على الفور‬
Okay! I'll put however many thumbprints you want!
‫حسنًا، سأبصم قدر ما تريد‬
If that's not enough, I'll put mine, too!
‫وإن لم تكفيك، سأبصم بدوري‬
Wait. What's the matter, Nami?
‫ماذا؟ ما الخطب يا نامي؟‬
There are three things I want to say, Mr. Appraiser.
‫ثمّة ثلاثة أشياء أريد قولها يا سيّدي المثمّن‬
First...
‫أوّلًا... نسيت أن أخبرك أنّ على رأس‬ ‫هذا الشّخص مكافأة مئة مليون‬
Second...
‫ثانيًا...‬
The appraisal you just gave us is unacceptable.
‫لا أقبل بالتّثمين الّذي منحتنا توًّا‬
Third... If you lie to us again...
‫وثالثًا... إن كذبت علينا ثانيةً، سنقتلع رأسك‬
That is all.
‫هذا كلّ شيء‬
Please...!
‫أنا... أنا آسف‬
Th-Three hundred million belly?! I'm not dreaming, am I?!
‫ثـ-ثلاثمئة مليون بيري؟ أليس هذا حُلمًا؟‬
Our adventure on Sky Island has finally paid off!
‫أثمرت مغامرتنا في جزيرة السّماء أخيرًا‬
I'm super rich!
‫أصبحتُ فاحشة الثّراء‬
– You mean "we"!
‫بل "أصبحنا"‬
I-I-I-It became 300 million! I-I'm scared!
‫أ-أ-أصبحت 300 مليون، أ-أنا خائف‬
I'm carrying 100 million?
‫أحمل 100 مليون؟‬
Wow, Nami's real good at making scary threats, huh?
‫تجيد نامي التّهديد حقًّا، صحيح؟‬
I estimated it at about this much from the start, but then he told us "100 million."
‫قدّرتُ ثمنه بذلك القدر من البداية‬ ‫لكنّه قال مئة مليون‬
You two couldn't play it cool, so he tried to pull a fast one.
‫كنتما مشوّشين، لذا لم يأخذنا على محمل الجدّ‬
Hey, Luffy! You shouldn't swing it around like that!
‫لوفي، إن لوّحت بها بتلك الطّريقة...‬
Well, anyway, I'm glad it went well.
‫على أيّ حال، أنا مسرور لأنّ الأمر سار بخير‬
– Ahh! The river!
‫النّهر‬
We're gonna lose 100 million belly to the river!
‫ستغرق المئة مليون بيري في النّهر‬
Phew! That was close!
‫كان ذلك وشيكًا‬
I'm gonna knock you out!
‫سأقضي عليك‬
I'm gonna break your teeth, you asshole!
‫سأكسر أسنانك أيّها الحقير‬
I-I'm... I'm sorry.
‫أ-أنا... آسف‬
"Identify yourselves"?
‫عرّفوا بأنفسكم‬
Pirate Hunter Zoro...
‫يا صائد القراصنة زورو...‬
We're bounty hunters whose name quiets even a crying child—
‫نحن صائدو مكافآت...‬
Your head's worth 60 million! We'll gratefully take it.
‫رأسك يساوي 60 مليون، سنأخذه بكلّ امتنان‬
Then, we'll wait in ambush inside your ship...
‫ثمّ سنختبئ في سفينتكم ونتربّص...‬
and catch the entire crew in one swoop.
‫ونقبض على سائر الطّاقم بانقضاض واحد‬
We'll make a killing! How lucky!
‫سنحقّق ثروة، يا لحظّنا‬
I'm first!
‫أنا الأوّل‬
"Lucky"?
‫"حظّ"؟‬
You mean unlucky, right?
‫تقصد "نحس"، صحيح؟‬
Stand tall!
‫لا تتوانوا‬
Two-Sword Style:
‫أسلوب السيفين‬ ‫نيتوريو‬
Rhino Cycle!
‫التفاف وحيد القرن‬ ‫ساي كورو‬
Dumbasses.
‫يا للتّفاهة...‬
Dammit!
‫سـ-سحقًا‬
S-S-Say, Nami... Maybe we really should take it back to the ship.
‫ا-اسمعي يا نامي، ربّما علينا أخذ‬ ‫المال إلى السّفينة فعلًا‬
That'd be a waste of time. The shipyard is right over this hill.
‫سيكون ذلك مضيعةً للوقت،‬ ‫الحوض خلف هذا التّلّ فحسب‬
Hey, I'm a bit shocked you guys won't let me near the money.
‫اسمعا، ما زلت في صدمة قليلًا لأنّكما‬ ‫لا تسمحان لي بالاقتراب من المال‬
Once we meet a shipwright,
‫فور أن نقابل سفانًا‬
we'll need to go back to the Merry with him right away for the repair estimate.
‫سيكون علينا الرّجوع إلى الميري‬ ‫لكي يقيّم رسوم الإصلاح...‬
I see.
‫فهمت‬
That seems about right.
‫هذا صحيح‬
I'm really not sure how to act. I've never carried around so much cash.
‫لا أدري ماذا أفعل، بما أنّني لم يسبق‬ ‫أن حملتُ معي هذا القدر من المال‬
Well, that's only natural.
‫حسنٌ، هذا طبيعي‬
What's unnatural is someone flailing it around.
‫لا أفهم لِمَ قد يقوم أحدهم بالتّلويح به‬
Ah! Hey, look over there! They're selling hydro buns!
‫انظرا إلى هناك، إنّهم يبيعون‬ ‫كعك الماء، لنشترِ 100 منها‬
– Shut up.
‫اخرس‬
Then, let's buy 1,000!
‫إذًا لنشترِ 1000 منها‬
Then...
‫إذًا...‬
– Shut up!
‫اخرس‬
O-Okay...
‫حاضر...‬
Here we are... back at the shipyard entrance.
‫عدنا إلى مدخل حوض السفانة‬
Good! Looks like the crowd from earlier is gone.
‫جيد، يبدو أنّ الحشد الّذي‬ ‫كان هنا سابقًا قد ذهب‬
Anyway, let's find... um... uh... What's his name again?
‫على أيّ حال، لنجد... ما كان اسمه؟‬
Mr. Iceburg.
‫أيسبرغ-سان‬
Right, that's it! Iceguy!
‫أجل، صحيح، العمّ أيس‬
I wonder who he is...
‫أتساءل من يكون‬
The old station lady told us to talk to him.
‫أخبرتنا الجدّة في المحطّة أن نسأل عنه‬
Yeah, she did...
‫صحيح...‬
More importantly, are we good to just walk on in?
‫الأهمّ، أتساءل ما إن كان لا بأس أن ندخل هكذا‬
I'm coming in!
‫سأدخل‬
– Not again!
‫ليس ثانيةً‬
Halt!
‫تمهّل‬
Hold your horses.
‫انتظر‬
Not a local?
‫أنت أجنبيّ، أليس كذلك؟‬
Only authorized individuals can amble about the shipyard.
‫فقط الأشخاص المصرّح لهم‬ ‫يمكنهم دخول المصنع‬
Oopsie-daisy.
‫ها أنا ذا‬
Kaku Shipwright Galley-La Company
‫كاكو‬ ‫سفان في شركة غاليلا‬ ‫سفانا في شركة غاليلا‬
Do you have some business at this dock?
‫هل لديكم عمل ما في هذا الحوض؟‬
Oh, it's you, Usopp.
‫إنّه أنت يا أوسوب‬
Hey! I'm right here, Luffy!
‫أنت، أنا بجانبك يا لوفي‬
Right! The nose is square-ish!
‫أجل. إنّه مربّع‬
Oh, yeah! Um...
‫صحيح، في الواقع... نريد مقابلة أيسبرغ-سان‬
Mr. Iceburg, you say? Are you a patron?
‫ماذا؟ أيسبرغ-سان؟ هل أنت زبونة؟‬
Why, it's plain as day.
‫فهمت‬
It appears to be a referral from old dame Kokoro at Shift Station.
‫هذه رسالة مرجعيّة من الجدّة كوكورو‬ ‫في محطّة التّحويل‬
Wha...? Are you old or something?
‫ماذا؟ هل أنت مُسن؟‬
I'm twenty-three.
‫عمري 23‬
For a twenty-three-year-old you sure talk like an old geezer.
‫عمرك 23... لكنّك تتحدّث كمُسنّ‬
Folks often tell me that.
‫يخبرني النّاس بذلك عادةً‬
So, do you know this Iceburg person?
‫إذًا... هل تعرف المدعو أيسبرغ؟‬
Know him? Why, Mr. Iceburg is the mayor of Water Seven.
‫أعرفه؟ في الواقع، أيسبرغ-سان‬ ‫هو عمدة ووتر سيفن‬
Huh... So he's some kinda big shot.
‫إنّه ذو شأن كبير إذًا؟‬
Not only is he the mayor, he's the president of Galley-La Company and manages the sea train.
‫ليس العمدة فحسب‬
So he's the top guy here!
‫إذًا هو الأكثر سلطة في البلدة؟‬
Why, in Water Seven, there isn't a soul who doesn't know him.
‫في الواقع، لا يوجد من لا يعرفه في ووتر سيفن‬
Where do we go to meet him?
‫أين يمكننا مقابلته؟‬
Oh... Where to find him right now...
‫أتساءل أين هو الآن‬
He's always buzzing about, which makes him a hard man to pin down.
‫قد يكون من الصّعب إيجاده‬ ‫لأنّه شخص مشغول جدًّا‬
Aw! Can't you reach out to him for us?
‫ألا يمكنك أن تتواصل معه أو ما شابه؟‬
I suppose it's possible... Is the matter urgent?
‫ذلك ممكن على الأغلب‬ ‫لكن... هل أنتم مستعجلون؟‬
It's not that we're in a hurry, but...
‫ليس أنّنا مستعجلون، لكن...‬
Essentially, you eager beavers want to talk about having your ship repaired, right?
‫باختصار، تريدون الحديث‬ ‫عن إصلاح سفينتكم، صحيح؟‬
Where did you drop anchor?
‫أين ترسو سفينتكم؟‬
Uh... Some place called Rocky Cape.
‫عند الرّأس الصّخري‬
Okey dokey. I'll pop on over and survey your ship's condition.
‫حسنًا إذًا، سأركض وأتفقّد حالة سفينتكم‬
It'll save some time when you see Mr. Iceburg.
‫سيوفّر لكم ذلك الوقت عندما‬ ‫تقابلون أيسبرغ-سان‬
You can talk about the repair fee, too.
‫يمكنكم الحديث عن رسوم الإصلاح أيضًا‬
"Pop on over"? As in, on a yagara bull?
‫"تركض"؟ على بُول من صنف ياغارا؟‬
If I do that, you'll be waiting a month of Sundays.
‫إن فعلتُ ذلك، فسأتأخّر عليكم،‬ ‫انتظروني لعشر دقائق فحسب‬
Ten minutes?
‫عشر دقائق؟‬
Precisely. Ten minutes.
‫صحيح، عشر دقائق‬
– He's fast! – Wh-Whoa!
‫يا لسرعته‬
Ahhh! He jumped!
‫عجبًا، لقد قفز‬
What?! But wait! Over there...
‫ماذا... لكن مهلًا، هنالك...‬
– ...is a drop-off!
‫جرف‬
He fell!
‫لقد سقط‬
Amazing!
‫مذهل‬
Is he okay?
‫أهو بخير؟‬
He runs...
‫إنّه يركض في البلدة بحريّة‬
Known as the Mountain Wind...
‫يدعوه النّاس بـ"رياح الجبل"‬
he's one of the foremen of Galley-La Company's Dock One:
‫إنّه رئيس سفّاني الحوض الأول‬ ‫من شركة غاليلا واسمه‬
Kaku.
‫كاكو‬
Well, well. I see.
‫هكذا إذًا... فهمت...‬
The City of Water... This is amazing!
‫مدينة الماء... هذا رائع‬
Clear springs and rivers... Clean streets and lively crowds...
‫ينابيع وأنهار صافية...‬ ‫شوارع نقيّة وشعب حيّ...‬
And many pretty women!
‫والكثير من النّساء الجميلات‬
I wanna take Nami or Robin out in a town like this!
‫أريد الخروج في موعد مع نامي-سان‬ ‫أو روبين-تشان في بلدة كهذه‬
Having a beauty on each arm would be nice too.
‫الخروج مع آنستين جميلتين‬ ‫سيكون جيّدًا أيضًا‬
This side is Nami, and this side is Robin.
‫في هذا الجانب نامي-سان‬ ‫وهذا الجانب روبين-تشان‬
Hey, mister.
‫يا سيّد، كفّ عن إبداء تلك التّعابير الغريبة‬
So which hydro cabbage are you gonna buy?
‫إذًا أيّ ملفوف ماء-ماء تريد أن تشتري؟‬
Which...? Ah, yes, I'll buy both.
‫ماذا؟ نعم، سأشتري كليهما، وأيضًا...‬
I'm looking for this town's in-season food... What's available?
‫أريد اقتناء طعام في موسمه‬ ‫من هذه البلدة، ما المتوفّر؟‬
Let's see. Huh? What the heck?
‫لنرَ... ماذا؟‬
Anyway, it's not so easy getting around on foot.
‫على أيّ حال، السّير غير مريح حقًّا‬
Another dead end? What a drag.
‫طريق مسدود آخر؟ تبًّا‬
Did I get lost? This is no good.
‫هل تهت؟ هذا سيّئ...‬
That's too much like a certain swordsmoron.
‫أشبه سيّافًا معيّنًا لعينًا‬
Oh! Robin!
‫روبين-تشان‬
Hello! It's me! Yoo-hoo! Robin my lo– Ah, uh... Huh?
‫مرحبًا، هذا أنا، مرحى‬
She disappeared...
‫اختفت؟‬
with no doors or walkways...?
‫بينما لا توجد أيّ أبواب أو أزقّة؟‬
Did she fly or something?
‫هل طارت أو ما شابه؟‬
Usopp...?
‫أوسوب؟‬
This town is a bit off. Or am I the one who's off here?
‫ما بال هذه البلدة؟ أم الخطب بي أنا؟‬
Why, that must be the ship.
‫لا بدّ أنّها تلك السّفينة‬
Pardon me.
‫المعذرة‬
Oh, it's just Usopp.
‫إنّه أوسوب‬
I see. It's damaged.
‫فهمت، إنّها متضرّرة‬
The mast needs to be replaced, too.
‫يجب استبدال الصّاري أيضًا‬
Usopp...?
‫أوسوب...‬
Hold it! Who the hell are you?!
‫مهلًا، من تكون يا هذا؟‬
Oh, forgive me. I interrupted your catnap.
‫آسف، أيقظتك‬
Oh, man! What a surprise!
‫يا إلهي... لقد ذُهلت‬
He jumped from there!
‫قفز من هناك‬
Well... my shipwrights are anything but ordinary.
‫إذًا... لا تستخفّوا بسفانيّي‬
So, who's this guy?
‫بالتّفكير في الأمر، من هذا الشّخص؟‬
Beats me.
‫لا أدري‬
If one so wishes to speedily build a faster, more capable vessel,
‫من أجل بناء سفينة أسرع وأقوى بسرعة‬
ordinary physical abilities just won't do.
‫يتطلّب الأمر أكثر من القدرة البدنيّة العاديّة‬
Kalifa, before we begin...
‫بالمناسبة يا كاليفا...‬
Yes, I've already checked.
‫نعم، سبق وتحقّقت‬
Straw Hat Luffy, Pirate Hunter Zoro, Nico Robin...
‫قبّعة القشّ لوفي وصائد القراصنة‬ ‫زورو ونيكو روبين...‬
Three members of his crew have bounties.
‫تملك مجموعتهم هؤلاء الثّلاثة‬ ‫بمكافآت على رؤوسهم‬
Total bounty: 239 million belly.
‫يُقدّر مجموع مكافآتهم بـ239 مليون بيري‬
Founded in the East Blue.
‫شُكّل الطّاقم في الأزرق الشّرقيّ‬
Known as the Straw Hats, seven crew members strong.
‫إنّه طاقم قبّعة القشّ‬ ‫ويملكون سبعة أعضاء حاليًّا‬
Th-They have us made.
‫يـ-يعرفوننا حقّ المعرفة‬
I see. I'm glad you came.
‫فهمت، مسرور لمجيئكم‬
Iceburg Water Seven Mayor & Galley-La Company President
‫أيسبرغ‬ ‫عمدة مدينة ووتر سيفن ورئيس شركة غاليلا‬
I'm Iceburg, the boss of this city.
‫أنا أيسبرغ، زعيم هذه المدينة‬
And this is a mouse I found earlier.
‫وهذا فأر وجدته سابقًا‬
His name is... let's see...
‫اسمه... لنرَ...‬
Tyrannosaurus.
‫تيرانوصور‬
I have to prepare his food and cage.
‫عليّ تجهيز طعامه وقفصه‬
Already taken care of, Mr. Iceburg.
‫سبق واهتممت بهما يا أيسبرغ-سان‬
Well, that's Kalifa for you.
‫هذا ما أتوقّعه منك‬
Thank you, sir.
‫شكرًا‬
Be advised,
‫الأهمّ، لديك موعد غداء مع مسؤول‬ ‫تنفيذيّ من مصنع زجاجيّات‬
After that, you'll give a speech at Liguria Plaza.
‫بعد ذلك، عليك إلقاء محاضرة‬ ‫في ساحة ليغوريا‬
When that's done, you have a conference with Mayor Bimine of Pucci, the Gourmet Town.
‫ثمّ بعدها لديك مؤتمر مع السّيّد بيميني‬ ‫عمدة بلدة الذّوّاقة، بوتشي‬
Their newspaper will also interview you.
‫فضلًا عن أنّك ستجري مقابلة صحفيّة هناك‬
Finally, you'll need to return to the office to finish a little paperwork.
‫بعدها، أرجو أن تعود إلى المكتب‬ ‫الرّئيسيّ وتراجع بعض المستندات‬
I don't want to!
‫لا أريد ذلك‬
Very well. I'll cancel them all.
‫حسنًا، سألغي كلّ شيء‬
Hey! Is that okay?!
‫مهلًا، ألا بأس بذلك؟‬
With all this clout, I can occasionally do something like that.
‫أنا رجل ذو سلطة تكفي لفعل أشياء كهذه‬
You're completely unfit to be a mayor.
‫أنت غير ملائم كعمدة حقًّا‬
That's pretty selfish of you!
‫يا لك من شخص أناني‬
So this guy is the one that old lady was talking about?
‫لكن أليس هذا الشّخص‬ ‫هو الّذي حدّثتنا عنه الجدّة؟‬
Yeah, he's that guy.
‫نعم، إنّه "ذلك الشّخص"‬
How shameless!
‫يا للوقاحة‬
What'd you do that for?!
‫لِمَ فعلت ذلك؟‬
Holy crap!
‫يا للهول‬
How dare you refer to one of the world's
‫أين أخلاقكم، إيّاكم أن تشيروا إلى أحد‬ ‫روّاد السفانة في العالم‬
Kalifa Iceburg's Beautiful Secretary
‫كاليفا‬ ‫سكرتيرة أيسبرغ الجميلة‬
leading shipwrights as "this guy" or "that guy"!?
‫بـ"ذلك الشّخص" و"هذا الشّخص"...‬
What's going on?
‫ما الّذي يجري؟‬
The secretary Kalifa had one of her rare explosions!
‫لقد انفعلت السّكرتيرة كاليفا‬ ‫للمرّة الأولى منذ مدّة‬
I wanna be kicked by her, too.
‫أريد أن تركلني أيضًا‬
Pardon me. I lost my composure for a moment.
‫المعذرة، فقدتُ هدوئي للحظة‬
Regardless, Mr. Iceburg is a local celebrity. Please mind your manners.
‫لكن، يحظى أيسبرغ-سان بإعجاب‬ ‫الشعب، تحلّوا بالآداب رجاءً‬
Try not to get Kalifa angry.
‫حاولوا ألاّ تغضبوا كاليفا‬ ‫لأنّها عندما تغضب...‬
she is indiscriminate.
‫تضرب عشوائيًّا‬
You kicked your own boss too!
‫ضربته بقسوة‬
Mind your own manners!
‫أنت من عليها أن تتهذّب‬
Ah, but anyway, you're Mr. Iceburg, right?
‫لكن على أيّ حال، أنت أيسبرغ-سان، صحيح؟‬
Please look at this. It's a referral.
‫انظر لهذه رجاءً، إنّها رسالة مرجعيّة‬
From old lady Kokoro...?
‫من الجدّة كوكورو...‬
"Take a look at their ship," huh...?
‫"ألقِ نظرة على سفينتهم"؟‬
What?! You won't?! Please! Please repair our ship!
‫ماذا؟ ألن تفعل؟ رجاءً‬ ‫أصلح سفينتنا رجاءً‬
We have money!
‫لدينا المال‬
The Merry is all beat up after our voyages!
‫لقد أُنهكت الميري بعد رحلاتنا، رجاءً يا عمّ‬
Okay.
‫حسنًا‬
Just like that! So it's okay?!
‫كم هذا طائش، ألا بأس؟‬
Yep.
‫نعم‬
Then why did you rip it up?
‫لِمَ مزّقتها إذًا؟‬
I can't stand her lipstick mark.
‫كانت علامة أحمر شفاهها بغيضة‬
Old lady Kokoro and I go way back as drinking buddies.
‫أنا والجدّة كوكورو كنّا نشرب‬ ‫معًا منذ وقتٍ طويل‬
Well, that aside, Kaku has already left to make an assessment.
‫حسنًا... ذهب كاكو بالفعل لإجراء تقييم‬
The matter is well underway. Don't fret.
‫نحن بصدد الأمر بالفعل، لا تقلقوا‬
I was bored today anyway.
‫اليوم مملّ على أيّ حال‬
Want a tour of the shipyard?
‫هل أريكم المصنع؟‬
Whoa! Seriously?
‫مذهل، حقًّا؟‬
Well then, follow me.
‫إذًا، من هنا رجاءً‬
This is the same man who just canceled his appointments...
‫أهذا أسلوب رجلٍ ألغى مواعيده؟‬
All right! We're gonna see the shipyard!
‫حسنًا، سنذهب إلى مصنع السفانة‬
Oh, right. The money.
‫صحيح، المال...‬
The money...? What?
‫المال...‬
Hm? Everything okay, Usopp?
‫ما الخطب يا أوسوب؟‬
Th-Th-The money... The money is gone!
‫ا-ا-المال... اختفى‬
Look everywhere!
‫ابحث جيّدًا‬
It's gone! I can't find it anywhere!
‫لا أستطيع إيجاده في أيّ مكان‬
Ah! Over there!
‫هناك‬
H-Hey, you crooks! What the hell?! Who are you?!
‫أ-أنتم أيّها الأوغاد،‬ ‫من أنتم يا هؤلاء؟ من أنتم؟‬
Why are you taking our money?!
‫لِمَ أخذتم مالنا؟‬
Hey! Hold it!
‫انتظروا‬
Thanks for the dough!
‫شكرًا للمال‬
Give us our money back!
‫أعيدوا لنا مالنا‬